Register of the Boris I. Nedzvetskii Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Boris I. Nedzvetskii papers,
1904-1970
2000C63
Nedzvetskii, Boris I.
2 microfilm reels. (0.3 linear feet)
Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, writings, and printed matter, relating to the scouting organization Natsional'naia Organizatsiia Russkikh Razvedchikov, and to Russian refugees in the Philippines.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Acquired.
Location of Originals
Originals in: Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco.
Biographical Note
Russian émigré scoutmaster in China and the United States.
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains the papers of Boris I. Nedzvetskii, an émigré active in scouting and monarchist organizations. In the subject file, of particular interest are the records of the Natsional'naia organizatsiia russkikh razvedchikov in China and the materials relating to the internment of Russian refugees from China at the Tubabao camp in the Philippines. The latter materials include also a number of issues of rare Tubabao information bulletins.
Detailed processing and preservation microfilming of these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and the Museum of Russian Culture. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials are held in the Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco, as its property. A transfer table of box and microfilm reel numbers is available at the Hoover Institution Archives.
The Hoover Institution assumes all responsibility for notifying users that they must comply with the copyright law of the United States (Title 17 United States Code) and Hoover Rules for the Use and Reproduction of Archival Materials.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the repository's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Natsional'naia organizatsiia russkikh razvedchikov.; Boy Scouts.; Russians--China.; Russians--Philippines.; Russians--United States.; Refugees.; Russia.; China.; Philippines.; United States.
Series Description
- Subject File, 1904-1970. (Box 1-2)
  Correspondence, orders, writings and printed matter, arranged alphabetically by heading
- Memorabilia, n.d.. (Box 2)
  Souvenir patches depicting Russian warships. Not filmed
Container List
- SUBJECT FILE, 1904-1970 (Box 1)
  - Holy Virgin Cathedral, San Francisco, California. (Folder 1: 1)
    Includes appeals, minutes and other matter, 1960-1962
  - Natsional'naia organizatsiia russkikh razvedchikov (NORR).
    Contains primarily materials relating to the organization in China
    - Lists of boy scouts (Folder 1: 2)
    - Orders
      - 1937-1939 (Folder 1: 3)
      - 1940-1944 (Folder 1: 4)
    - Printed matter. Opolchenets, #1-15 (1938-1939) and one unnumbered issue from 1942 (Folder 1: 5)
    - Miscellany (Folder 1: 6)
  - Petrovskii soiuz. Order #1 (1939) (Folder 1: 7)
  - Refugee camps--Tubabao, Philippines, 1948-1950
    - Printed matter
      - Ezhenedel'noe obozrenie, #1 (1949 December) - 5 (1950 February) (Folder 1: 8)
      - Nash golos, #1 (1949 April 24) - 9 (1949 July 12), 12 (1949 August 31) (Folder 1: 9)
      - Nash vestnik, #1-15 and special issues (1951 January)., Actually published by Tubabao refugees aboard the U.S.N.S. General W. G. Haan, en route to the U.S. (Folder 1: 10)
      - Tubabao znaet, #1 (1949 April 24) - 3, 6-15, 17 (1949 September 23) (Folder 1: 11)
    - Miscellany (Folder 1: 12)
  - Romanov, House of., Many of the writings appear to be by V. V. Seifullin (Box 2)
    - General, n.d. (Folder 2: 1)
    - "Imperatorskaia Rossiia," n.d. (Folder 2: 2)
    - "Istoricheskaia pravda o bylom mogushchestvie i slavie moei velikoi rodiny Rossii," n.d. (Folder 2: 3)
      Holograph
  - Russians--China--Shanghai (Folder 2: 4)
  - Unidentified flying objects, 1963-1966. (Folder 2: 5)
    Bulletins of British UFO study groups, along with correspondence
  - Miscellany, 1904-1970. (Folder 2: 6-7)
    Clippings and leaflets on a variety of subjects including Russian history and émigré life in China. Includes issues of Golos Rossii (1932), Russkaia gazeta (Shanghai), 1949, and other periodicals
- MEMORABILIA, n.d., Not filmed. (Folder 2: 8)
  Souvenir patches depicting Russian warships